[Grant Sanderson] if i think of like the early days of
[Grant Sanderson] khan academy and like the ted talks that
[Grant Sanderson] you gave or
[Grant Sanderson] the book that you wrote there's a kind
[Grant Sanderson] of um
[Grant Sanderson] there's an optimism around it and also
[Grant Sanderson] an ambition right there's like this is
[Grant Sanderson] this is what the world could look like
[Grant Sanderson] or this is what education could be
[Grant Sanderson] and aside from that i was like and let's
[Grant Sanderson] start to build it let's actually start
[Grant Sanderson] to make it
[Grant Sanderson] uh like where where is your current mind
[Grant Sanderson] when you're thinking about the next
[Grant Sanderson] decade or the next two decades of
[Grant Sanderson] education
[Sal Khan] i continue to be optimistic although i
[Sal Khan] have i think a better appreciation for
[Sal Khan] the complexity
[Sal Khan] not you know including just the
[Sal Khan] complexity of of of running an
[Sal Khan] organization or multiple organizations
[Sal Khan] but also
[Sal Khan] how that interfaces with the broader
[Sal Khan] with the broader world
[Sal Khan] when i first wrote khan academy's
[Sal Khan] mission statement it was really
[Sal Khan] i was just trying to fill out the
[Sal Khan] paperwork with the irs as quickly as
[Sal Khan] possible so i could get the
[Sal Khan] not-for-profit status
[Sal Khan] you know it was delusional when a one
[Sal Khan] guy in a walk-in closet is writing free
[Sal Khan] world-class education for anyone
[Sal Khan] anywhere and even then i recognize it's
[Sal Khan] a mission it's not something you're just
[Sal Khan] going to be able to like
[Sal Khan] solve in the next two or three years but
[Sal Khan] if you fast forward to now
[Sal Khan] i think 2008 sal who was or seven sal
[Sal Khan] who was filling out that paperwork
[Sal Khan] would have been blown away by how far
[Sal Khan] khan academy has gotten and
[Sal Khan] to some degree how legitimate it's
[Sal Khan] viewed and
[Sal Khan] and how we we work with systems and how
[Sal Khan] many people are using it
[Sal Khan] but 2021 sal myself
[Sal Khan] knows that that's nice 2007 sal i know
[Sal Khan] this is getting a little weird
[Sal Khan] but but as many people are using it and
[Sal Khan] as much as we've done
[Sal Khan] we're still making a relatively small
[Sal Khan] dent
[Sal Khan] relative to the overall issue of
[Sal Khan] we generally want billions of people to
[Sal Khan] become actualized
[Sal Khan] to become actualized in their lives and
[Sal Khan] i do think that khan academy can play a
[Sal Khan] role catalyzing this in terms of the
[Sal Khan] the underlying philosophy around mastery
[Sal Khan] based learning personalization
[Sal Khan] i keep coming back to it and it's be it
[Sal Khan] you know
[Sal Khan] every now and then there's this
[Sal Khan] temptation to say well that's not where
[Sal Khan] other people are
[Sal Khan] let's tweak it a little bit to be a
[Sal Khan] little bit more mainstream
[Sal Khan] and then you just but then you realize
[Sal Khan] the truth of it over and over and over
[Sal Khan] again so yes we will we are doing things
[Sal Khan] at khan academy
[Sal Khan] that help work with a traditional
[Sal Khan] workflow or a traditional classroom that
[Sal Khan] might not be mastery based because
[Sal Khan] there's still value in
[Sal Khan] using khan academy as a supplement using
[Sal Khan] it
[Sal Khan] as the go-to place for practice getting
[Sal Khan] immediate feedback getting micro lessons
[Sal Khan] so we want to make sure it's used in
[Sal Khan] that way
[Sal Khan] but we want to make sure also that we
[Sal Khan] never lose our core principle that the
[Sal Khan] ideal is mastery based learning
[Sal Khan] differentiation personalization
[Sal Khan] i think we have helped put it into the
[Sal Khan] zeitgeist
[Sal Khan] you hear a lot more people talking about