[Grant Sanderson] If I think of like the early days of Khan Academy
[Grant Sanderson] and like the TED talks that you gave
[Grant Sanderson] or the book that you wrote, there's a
[Grant Sanderson] kind of, um, there's an optimism around it and also an ambition, right?
[Grant Sanderson] There's like, this is, this is what the
[Grant Sanderson] world could look like, or this is what education could be.
[Grant Sanderson] And aside from that, I was like, and let's start to build it.
[Grant Sanderson] Let's actually start to make it.
[Grant Sanderson] Uh, like where, where is your current
[Grant Sanderson] mind when you're thinking about the next decade
[Grant Sanderson] or the next two decades of education?
[Sal Khan] I continue to be optimistic, although I
[Sal Khan] have, I think, a better appreciation for the complexity, not,
[Sal Khan] you know, including this complexity of
[Sal Khan] running an organization or multiple organizations,
[Sal Khan] but also how that interfaces with the broader world.
[Sal Khan] When I first wrote Khan Academy's mission statement, it was really,
[Sal Khan] I was just trying to fill out the
[Sal Khan] paperwork with the IRS as quickly as possible
[Sal Khan] so that I could get the not-for-profit status.
[Sal Khan] You know, it was delusional when a one
[Sal Khan] guy in a walk-in closet is writing
[Sal Khan] free world-class education for anyone anywhere.
[Sal Khan] And even then, I recognize it's a mission.
[Sal Khan] It's not something that you're just going to be able to like,
[Sal Khan] Solve in the next two or three years But if you fast-forward to now,
[Sal Khan] I think 2008 Sal who was or seven Sal who was filling out
[Sal Khan] that paperwork would have been blown away
[Sal Khan] by how far Khan Academy has gotten and
[Sal Khan] to some degree how legitimate it's viewed and
[Sal Khan] And how we work with systems and how many people are using it
[Sal Khan] But 2021 Sal, myself, knows that that's nice.
[Sal Khan] 2007 Sal, I know this is getting a little weird.
[Sal Khan] But as many people are using it and
[Sal Khan] as much as we've done, we're still making
[Sal Khan] a relatively small dent relative to the overall
[Sal Khan] issue of we genuinely want billions of
[Sal Khan] people to become actualized in their lives.
[Sal Khan] And I do think that Khan Academy can
[Sal Khan] play a role catalyzing this in terms
[Sal Khan] of the underlying philosophy around
[Sal Khan] mastery-based learning, personalization.
[Sal Khan] I keep coming back to it and it's, you know, every now
[Sal Khan] and then there's this temptation to say,
[Sal Khan] well, that's not where other people are.
[Sal Khan] Let's tweak it a little bit to be a little bit more mainstream.
[Sal Khan] And then you just, but then you realize
[Sal Khan] the truth of it over and over and over again.
[Sal Khan] So yes, we will, we are doing things at Khan Academy
[Sal Khan] that help work with the traditional
[Sal Khan] workflow or traditional classroom that might
[Sal Khan] not be mastery based because there's still value
[Sal Khan] in using Khan Academy as a supplement
[Sal Khan] using it as the go-to place
[Sal Khan] for practice, getting immediate feedback, getting micro lessons.
[Sal Khan] So we want to make sure it's used in that way.
[Sal Khan] But we want to make sure also that
[Sal Khan] we never lose our core principle that
[Sal Khan] the ideal is mastery-based learning, differentiation, personalization.
[Sal Khan] I think we have helped put it into the zeitgeist.
[Sal Khan] You hear a lot more people talking about